SANNU AHMED

HEALTH EDUCATION CONSULTANT



+977 9814006437



pr.sannu.ahmed@gmail.com



Barharia, Siwan, India

PROFILE

I am a qualified pharmacist with six years of experience as a health education consultant. Trained primary level teachers, students, and mother's group about health and healthy lifestyles. Strong creative and analytical skills. Team player with an eye for detail.

SKILLS

- Keeping up to date with developments in the pharmaceutical industry
- Good pharmacy practices
- Able to provide face to face customer interaction
- A thorough understanding of various drugs, medical terminologies and abbreviations
- Public speaking
- Writing Skill
- ·Time management skill
- Basic computer knowledge
- Problem-Solving
- Strong Communication

EDUCATION

SECONDARY SCHOOL

2004-2005

Tulashi mehar memorial boarding 54.25%

DIPLOMA IN PHARMACY 2007-2009

Kantipur college of medical science Distinction

BACHELOR IN PHARMACY 2010-2014

Mallige college of pharmacy

Distinction

EXPERIENCE

HEALTH EDUCATION CONSULTANT

SOLIDARITY FOR DEVELOPMENT (NGO), CHRISTINE'S DISPENSARY, BIR HOSPITAL

2018 - Present

- To educate students and mother on importance of nutrition in
- To provide public health education in Christine's dispensary, Bir Hospital
- To train mothers group on basic first aid in rural areas
- To train mothers group about basic yogasana and pranayam in rural areas
- To provide training to MGML teachers on health subject
- Responsible for distribution of medicine to the poor and needy patient (Both out-patient as well as in patient)
- To dispense medicine and counsel patient during health camp
- To educate people and students on emerging health topics during health camp
- To prepare reports
- To maintain medicines stock record up-to-date
- To check expiry of drug on monthly basis
- To give proper advice on future strategies to run the organization efficiently

VOLUNTEER

SOLIDARITY FOR DEVELOPMENT (NGO), CHRISTINE'S DISPENSARY, BIR HOSPITAL

2016-2017

- Responsible for providing health education to people in Christine's dispensary, Bir Hospital
- Responsible for dispensing medicine to the poor and needy patient
- To dispense medicine and counsel patient during health camp
- To educate people and students on emerging health topics during health camp
- To prepare reports
- To maintain medicines stock record up-to-date
- To check expiry of drug on monthly basis

PHARMACEUTICAL MICROBIOLOGY INSTRUCTOR (PART TIME)

NATIONAL ACADEMY FOR MEDICAL SCIENCE 2017-2021

- · To teach pharmaceutical microbiology
- To carry out microbiological laboratory experiments

SUPERVISOR

UNIVERSAL AMUSEMENTS PVT. LTD

2014-2016

- To educate the staff on the handling of chemicals and glass wares
- To prepare the guide book for the quantity of chemicals needed to carry on the reaction
- ·To prepare the chemical solutions
- ·To support during stage program carried out in schools
- ·To ensure overall safety during stage program

PROFESSIONAL COURSE

- Postgraduate diploma in Clinical research
- Postgraduate diploma in Pharmacovigilence

TRAININGS

- Basic first aid
- · Psychosocial first aid
- Health and nutrition
- Stigmatization and discrimination reduction to HIV/AIDS people
- · WASH training
- Report writing, proposal writing and case study writing
- Yoga- Yogasanas, Pranayam and Dhyanam

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Attended seminar on "Recent trend in drug discovery"
- Attended seminar on "Entrepreneurship in pharmacy"
- Attended seminar on "Advance technique in experimental pharmacology"
- Attended seminar on "Good pharmacy practice"

PUBLICATIONS

- · Published book on "Patient Counseling"
- Published book on "Pharmacology for Nurses"
- Published book on "pharmaceutics-I for diploma students"
- Published book on "pharmacology- I & II for diploma students"
- Published book on "pharmaceutical chemistry-II for diploma students"

AWARDS

- Academic excellence scholarship award in 2nd & 3rd year of diploma in pharmacy
- Best outgoing student award during graduation ceremony
- Won trophies and medals for singing, dancing, and outdoor games

INTERESTS

 I enjoy researching, reading, traveling and surfing the internet.

REFERENCES

Mr. Bhuwan Prasad Awasthi Postdoctoral research associate The University of British Columbia, Canada (+1) 6047160411

Mr. Pradip Regmi

Lecturer

Nepal institute of health sciences- Stupa College, Nepal

Mob: +977 9818383257

Mr. Ekraj Sapkota

Dispensary incharge

Solidarity for development, Bir hospital, Nepal

Mob: +977 9851277782